FAIZAN ALI TARIQ

PERSONAL INFORMATION

• House # 146/7. TIP Housing Society Haripur

+92 311 0868792

EDUCATION

BSc Mechatronics Engineering 2012-2016

University of Wah

CGPA = 2.87

Majors

- Microcontroller Based Design
- ➤ Embedded Systems
- > Electronic Devices and Circuit
- ➤ Machine Design and CAD/CAM
- > Theory of Machine
- > Robotics

Projects

- Modeling and Control of Two Wheeled Self-Balancing Robot
- Controlling speed & direction of motor using PIC microcontroller
- ➤ Interfacing of I2C based on Inertial Measurement Unit (MPU-6050)
- ➤ 3D modeling of Masjid using Sherline CNC milling Machine
- ➤ Data Communication on 8 bit LCD

FSc Pre Engineering 2010-2012

Hazara Public School and College Haripur Marks = 72%

Matric Computer Science 2008-2010

Merit Schooling System

Marks = 73%

SKILLS

- ➤ Solid Works
- > CREO
- Micro-Controller Programming
- > CNC Programming
- > MATLAB
- ➤ Proteus
- > MS-Office

CAREER SUMMARY

Internee Administrative Assistant with one year of post qualification experience in Management and Internee Engineer with three months of experience in Ministry of Defense Production. Proficiency in Management and CAD/CAM. Looking to lift up well reputed organizations and myself through my knowledge and experience.

WORK EXPERIENCE

University of Haripur

Internship 15/07/2017 - 30/06/2018

Provided services in:

- > Technical support.
- ➤ Control Internet Connectivity System.
- > Manage conferences and workshops.
- > Manipulate the complaints.

National Radio and Telecommunication Corporation

Internship 29/05/2017 – 28/08/2017

Delivered services in:

- ➤ Material and Manufacturing Sector
- ➤ Operate different manufacturing machines e.g. CNC Milling, CNC Lathe, Wire Cut EDM, Plastic Injection Molding.
- ➤ Used CAD software's e.g. Solid Works and Creo.

Pakistan Ordnance Factories, Wah Cantt

Internship 06/08/2015 - 03/09/2015

Worked in three different factories:

- Services Factory
- ➤ Weapons Factory
- > Small Arm Ammunition Factory

Telephone Industries of Pakistan, Haripur

Internship 11/08/2014 - 10/09/2014

Worked in:

➤ Electronics Production Department.

Knowledge in production of communication products.

CERTIFICATION

- ➤ MS Word 2013 Specialist
- > PEC Registered
- > Supervision

REFERENCES

Available upon request